Mss.B.Al1 Mss.B.AL1
American Philosophical Society
Album materials
1777-1925
Mss.B.AL1
American Philosophical Society
0.25 Linear feet
Materials removed from albums, of letters and autographs of various persons.
Various authors
Box 1
Scope and Contents note
This collection is composed of material taken from various albums. It includes letters between prominent scientists, including David Brewster, Francis Buckland Charles Bonaparte, and Herbert Spencer.
The majority of correspondence is friendly letters, and topics discussed include astronomy, natural history and fossils. Also included are autographs from Ulysses S. Grant, Lewis Boss, David Brewster and Verney Lovett Cameron among others.
Early American History Note
This autograph collection contains only a few letters from early America. They were acquired for the signficiance of their signature - often British scientists - and not for their content.
Autographs.; Beyond Early America; Correspondence.
- Papers
  - Letter to Edmund Balfour, Oct., 1815; 8x6; Abernethy, John, 1764-1831
    Scope and Contents note
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.17.) Business.
  - Letter to Dr. Dobie, March 1, 1885; 7x4-1/2; Acland, Henry W. (Henry Wentworth), 1815-1900
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Album 1, pp.185-186.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John Thomas] Quekett, Dec. 22, 1860; 7x4-1/2; Acland, Henry W. (Henry Wentworth), 1815-1900
    A.L.S. 3p.and end. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.24.) Friendly letter. Refers to a telescope and a portable microscope.
  - Letter to ----, 3-1/2x5-1/2; Acland, Henry W. (Henry Wentworth), 1815-1900
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. III, p.11.) Concerning earthquakes.
  - Letter to H[erbert] H[all] Turner, July 18, 1911; 7x4-1/2; Anderson, Thomas D
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.17.) Friendly letter. Concerning astronomy.
  - Letter to ----, September 18; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Ansted, D. T. (David Thomas), 1814-1880
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Album 2, p.101.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. Percy, May 27; 8x5; Armstrong, W. G. (William George), Baron, 1810-1900
    A.L.S. 1p (see Album 1, pp.4-5.) Refuses an invitation.
  - Letter to ----, July 12; 8x6; Babbage, Charles, 1791-1871
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.12.) Asks favors.
  - Letter to [Herbert Hall] Turner, May 3, 1906; 7x4-1/2; Ball, Robert S. (Robert Stawell), 1840-1913
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.19.) Friendly letter. Concerning astronomy.
  - Letter to [William] Quekett, Oct. 24, 1876; 7x4-1/2; Beale, Lionel S. (Lionel Smith), 1828-1906
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.24.) Needs F.T. Buckland's signature.
  - Recommendation of E[dwin John] Quekett, July 29, 1834; 9x7-1/2; Bell, Charles, Sir, 1774-1842
    A.D.S. 1p.,end. (see Albums...;1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.19.)
  - Address, Oct. 5, 1857; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Biot, Jean Baptiste, 1774-1862
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Album 1, pp.228-229.)
  - Letter to ----, Blackie, John Stuart
    A.L.S. 1 p.
  - Letter to ----, Blackie, John Stuart
  - Letter to Monsieur Clift, Paris, October 29, 1819; 10x8; Blagden, Charles, Sir, 1748-1820
    A.L.S. 1p., add., enclosure wanting. Friendly letter. Concerning anatomy. Refers to Cuvier.
  - Letter to [John Thomas] Quekett, July 9, 1860; 6x4; Blair, V N ?
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p. 6.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Sir] Richard Owen, London, Sept. 5, 1839; 11x8-1/2; Bonaparte, Charles Lucian, 1803-1857
    Rome, A.L.S. 2p.,add.,end. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol.IV, p.10.) Concerning his publication.
  - Autograph., 1x3; Boss, Lewis, 1846-1912
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Albums...;1777-1917. Vol. II, p.31.)
  - Letter to H[erbert] H[all] Turner, March, 1901; 10-1/2x8; Boss, Lewis, 1846-1912
    Albany, A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.20.) Introduces people interested in astronomy.
  - Autograph, April 22, 1847; 1-1/2x4-1/2; Brewster, David, Sir, 1781-1868
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. II, p.49.) Removed from letter.
  - Receipt to Wellswood school, Feb. 4, 1910; 4x7; British Antarctic ("Terra Nova") Expedition (1910-1913)
    Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: R. Scott. 1p. (see Album 2, p.91.) Not found April, 2011.
  - Letter to Miss L. M. Oldfield, Jan. 16, 1891; 10-1/2x8-1/2; British Museum
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W. H. Flower. 2p. (see Album 2, p.106.) Thanks for donation.
  - Letter to Bagshaw, Dec. 30, 1894; 6x4; Broadbent, William H. (William Henry), 1835-1907
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Album 1, pp. 88-89.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [William?] Clift, 7x4-1/2; Brodie, Benjamin, Sir, 1783-1862
    Saturday night. A.L.S. 2p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.2.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mr. Dodd, Feb. 6, 1871; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Buckland, Francis T. (Francis Trevelyan), 1826-1880
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Album 1, p.214.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to ----, Feb. 13, 1866; 9x7; Buckland, Francis T. (Francis Trevelyan), 1826-1880
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Album 2, p.105.) Sends slice of salmon.
  - Letter to ----, February 25; 6-1/2x4-1/2; Buckland, Francis T. (Francis Trevelyan), 1826-1880
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. vol. V, p.2.) Concerning parasites in a fox.
  - Letter to ----, 7-1/2x4-1/2; Buckland, Francis T. (Francis Trevelyan), 1826-1880
    Saturday. A.L.S. 3p. In pencil. (see Album 2, p.104.) Will show a whale to his little boy.
  - Letter to W[illiam] Clift, July 31, 1821; 9x7; Buckland, William, 1784-1856
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.13.) Concerning fossil bones.
  - Letter to ----, June 20, [1846?]; 7x4-1/2; Buckland, William, 1784-1856
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Album 1, p.141.) Friendly letter.
  - Autograph., 1x3-1/2; Cameron, Verney Lovett, 1844-1894
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. II, p.39.)
  - Letter to Burrows, Oct., 1876; 7x4-1/2; Cameron, Verney Lovett, 1844-1894
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Album 2, p.93.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Sir] A[stley] P. Cooper, bart., March 10, 1838; 9x7-1/2; Carlisle, Anthony, Sir, 1768-1840
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p. 15.) Concerning the future of the surgical college. Refers to Brodie.
  - Autograph., 4x7; Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Album 2, p.41.) Not found April, 2011.
  - Autograph., 3x7-1/2; Chalmers, Thomas, 1780-1847
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Album 2, p.95.) Removed from a letter.
  - Letter to ----, Sept. 27, 1761; 7x4-1/2; Charconne, Jean
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Album 1, pp.228-229.) Concerning stellar observations.
  - Letter to Mrs. Edwards, 5-1/2x3-1/2; Christie, William Henry Mahoney, Sir, 1845-1922
    Merionethshire, Tuesday. A.L.S. 4p. (see Album 1, pp.8-9.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. Edwards, Dec. 25, 1902; 6-1/2x4; Cobbe, Frances Power, 1822-1904
    A.L.S. 4p.and add. (see Album 1, pp.308-309.) Friendly letter. Not found April, 2011.
  - Letter to Mrs. Edwards, 7x4-1/2; Cobbe, Frances Power, 1822-1904
    Dolgelley, A.L.S. 4p. (see Album 1, pp.189-190.) Forwards autographs. Not found April, 2011.
  - Letter to Thomson, Feb. 24, 1899; 8x5; Collin, J Norman
    London, A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums.. .; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.4.) Refuses invitation.
  - Letter to [William] Clift., 7x4-1/2; Cooper, Astley, Sir, 1768-1841
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Albums.. .; 1777-1917. Vol.IV, p.3.) Asks a favor.
  - Letter to ----, 7x4-1/2; Cooper, Astley, Sir, 1768-1841
    Filey, A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. VII, p.17.) Presents publication. Not found April, 2011.
  - Autograph., 1x3-1/2; Cornwallis, Charles Cornwallis, Marquis, 1738-1805
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Album 2, p.27.) Not found April, 2011.
  - Poem, Sept. 29, 1842; 4x6; Crosse, Andrew, 1784-1855
    A.D.S. 1p. ( see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.9. )
  - Letter to ----, Jan. 16, 1836; 9x7; Cuvier, Frédéric, 1773-1838
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p.and end. In French. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.4.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Owen, May 8, 1847; 7x4-1/2; De La Beche, Henry T. (Henry Thomas), 1796-1855
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.16.) Wishes to meet him at the geological society. Concerning fossil fishes and Sir Philip Egerton.
  - Address., 3x4-1/2; Derby, Edward Smith Stanley, Earl of, 1775-1851
    D.S. 1p. (see Album 1, pp.215-216.) Not found April, 2011.
  - Letter to Lord R. Mardale[?], London, July 30, 1899; 8x5; Devonshire, Spencer Compton Cavendish, Duke of, 1833-1908
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Album 1, pp.288-289.) Concerning an appointment.
  - Letter to John Milne, April 30 1911; Darwin, George Howard, Sir, 1845-1912
  - Autograph, Dawes, William Rutter
  - Letter to Mrs. [Amy Menella Dodgson?] Pollock, Oct. 7, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Dewar, James, Sir, 1842-1923
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Album 1, pp.113-114.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Herbert Hall] Turner, Dec. 27, 1911; 7x4-1/2; Donner, Anders Severin, 1854-1938
    Helsingfors, A.L.S. 3p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.19.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Miss de Matorp, Oct. 16, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Edwards, Amelia Ann Blanford, 1831-1892
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Album 1, pp.288-289.) Friendly letter.
  - Note to [Bartlett?]., 7x4-1/2; Ericksen, John E
    A.N.S. 1p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.23.) Asks question. On Same sheet as letter from William Fergusson to [J.E.] Ericksen; Dec. 18, 1873. Not found April, 2011.
  - Letter to Edm[un]d Balfour, Jan. 23, 1840; 7x4-1/2; Faraday, Michael, 1791-1867
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.6.) Regrets he cannot become a member of the royal college of surgeons.
  - Letter to [E.P.?] Oldfield, June 24, 1876; 6x4; Fergusson, James, 1808-1886
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Album 2, p.45.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John E.] Ericksen, Dec. 18, 1873; 7x4-1/2; Fergusson, William, Sir, 1808-1877
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.23.) Concerning an appointment. On same letter is note by John E. Ericksen to [Bartlett?].
  - Letter to [John Thomas] Quekett, Aug. 19, 1854; 7x4-1/2; Forbes, Edward, 1815-1854
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.12.) Refers a question on Egypt.
  - Note to Herbert Thompson, London, Oct. 11, [1887?]; 3x5; Foster, Michael, Sir, 1836-1907
    A.N.S.with initials on postal card. 1p. (see Album 1, pp. 185-186.) Friendly note.
  - Letter to "my dear Craik" [Crake?], May 9, 1886; 8x5; Freeman, Edward Augustus, 1823-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Album 1, p.85.) Friendly letter. Refers to T. A. Trollope.
  - Letter to [Charles Hamilton] Aidé, April 12; 7x4-1/2; Froude, James Anthony, 1818-1894
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Album 1, pp.6-7.) Friendly letter.
  - Autograph, Froude, James Anthony, 1818-1894
  - Letter to _____ Milne, Nov. 4, 1911; Galitzin, B.
  - Letter to _____ Milne, July 21, 1912; Galitzin, B.
  - Letter to ----., 2-1/2x6; Gasparis, Annibal de, 1819-
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Fragment. (see Album 1, pp.230-231.) Friendly letter.
  - Autograph (removed from letter to Professor Thomson)., 1-1/2x4-1/2; Geddes, W. D. (William Duguid), 1828-1900
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Album...; 1777-1917. Vol.II, p.65.) Not found April, 2011.
  - Letter to E. W. Thomson, March 6, 1886; 6x4; Geddes, W. D. (William Duguid), 1828-1900
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. I, p.48.) Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Miss Barton, Jan. 25, 1899; Geikie, James, 1839-1915
    Edinburgh, A.L.S. 1p. Informs Barton there is "no immediate hurry. I hardly expect that any peat-cutting can be done before April or May."
  - Autograph., 1x3-1/2; Gibb, Elias John Wilkinson, 1857-1901
    D.S. 1p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. vol. I, p.54.)
  - Letter to Mrs. Thomson, May 30, 1910; 7x4-1/2; Gill, David, Sir, 1843-1914
    London, A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.25.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. Thomson, Oct. 2, 1910; 7x4-1/2; Gill, David, Sir, 1843-1914
    London, A.L.S. 2p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.28.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. Thomson, Oct. 14, 1911; 7x4-1/2; Gill, David, Sir, 1843-1914
    Kensington, A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.3.) Will preside at a meeting.
  - Letter to ----, Nov. 20, 1857; 7x4-1/2; Glaisher, James, 1809-1903
    Lewisham, A.L.S. 1p. (see Album 1, pp.228-229.) Concerning an award of the royal astronomical society of London.
  - Letter to [John?] Milne, Nov. 4, 1911; 8x5; Golitsyn, B. B. (Boris Borisovich), 1862-1916
    St. Petersburg, A.L.S. 3p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.15.) Concerning the publications of the imperial academy of sciences of St. Petersburg. Not found April 2011.
  - Letter to [Herbert Hall Turner], Jan. 23; 6x4; Goschen, George Joachim Goschen, Viscount, 1831-1907
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p. 22.) Friendly letter.
  - Autograph., 1-1/2x4; Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Album 2, p.35.) Not found April, 2011.
  - Letter to ----, June 5, 1847; 7x4-1/2; Grove, W. R. (William Robert), 1811-1896
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.9.) Concerning force. Refers to Faraday.
  - Letter to Durham, April 26, 1873; 7x4-1/2; Gull, William Withey, Sir, 1816-1890
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Album 1, pp.88-89.) Asks to borrow a book.
  - Letter to [Edward] Clodd, Feb. 9, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Haddon, Alfred C. (Alfred Cort), 1855-1940
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 2p. (see Albums ..; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p. 6.) Introduces Dr. Sterling.
  - Letter to Thomson, Jan. 17, 1900; 7x4-1/2; Hare, Charles
    London, A.L.S. 2p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.28.) Natural history.
  - Letter to J[ohn Thomas] Quekett, Aug. 27, 1845; 6x4-1/2; Hassall, Arthur Hill, 1817-1894
    London, A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.12.) Asks a favor.
  - Letter to Cornelius Paine, Oct. 26, 1870; 7x4-1/2; Hazlitt, William Carew, 1834-1913
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Album 1, pp.292-293.) Will sell some of his rare books.
  - Autograph., 3x7-1/2; Helps, Arthur, Sir, 1813-1875
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Album 2, p.51.) Removed from a letter to Earl Russell.
  - Autograph., 3x4-1/2; Hooker, William Jackson, Sir, 1785-1865
    D.S. 1p. (See Album 1, p.195.) Removed from a letter.
  - Letter to [Edward] Clodd, July 8, 1901; 7x4; Huggins, William, Sir, 1824-1910
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.3.) Gives him a pass.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Amy Menella Dodgson?] Pollock, Nov. 13, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Huggins, William, Sir, 1824-1910
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Album 1, pp.113-114.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Herbert Hall] Turner, Aug. 21, 1902; 7x4; Huggins, William, Sir, 1824-1910
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.19.) Concerning astronomy.
  - Letter to E[dward] Clodd, Nov. 6, 1893; 8x5; Hughes, David Edward, 1830-1900
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.2.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Hermann Rudolph Alfred von] Schlaginteweit[-Sakünlünski], Dec. 1, 1857; 8-1/2 x 5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. by John Quekett. In English and German. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.5.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Edward] Jenner, Gloucestershire, Aug. 20, 1777; 9x7-1/2; Hunter, John, 1728-1793
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.2.) Will visit him.
  - Letter to [John Russell] Hind, London, Feb. 12, 1857; 10-1/2x8; Institut de France. Académie des sciences
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Flourens. 1p.and add. In French. (see Album 1, pp.230-231.) Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Munro [Edwards], May 9, 1867; 7x4-1/2; Johns, C. A. (Charles Alexander), 1811-1874
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Album 1, pp.302-303.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to C. E. M. Edwards, Eton, June 2, 1872; 7x4-1/2; Johns, Charles Alexander, 1811-1874
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Album 1, pp.302-303.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John Thomas] Quekett, Nov. 3, 1853; 7x4-1/2; Jones, Bence, 1814-1873
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.12.) Introduces Robert Brown.
  - Autograph., 1-1/2x3-1/2; Jones, J. V. (John Viriamu), 1856-1901
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol.II, p.6.)
  - Autograph, Jussieu, Adrien de, 1798-1853
  - Letter to [William Govett] Romaine, Dec. 25, 1874; 7x4-1/2; KInglake, John A.W., Sir
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Album 1, p.196.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to H[erbert] H[all] Turner, Oxford, Jan. 22, 1910; 10x8; Küshner, F
    Bonn, A.L.S. 2p.,end. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. v, p.21.) Astronomy. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Lady [Harriet Ann Hooker Thistleton-] Dyer, March 27, 1900; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Lankester, E. Ray (Edwin Ray), Sir, 1847-1929
    Nice, A.L.S. 2p. (see Album 1, pp.200-201.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Lady [Harriet Ann Hooker Thistleton-] Dyer, April 7; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Lankester, E. Ray (Edwin Ray), Sir, 1847-1929
    Monaco, A.L.S. 2p. (see Album 1, pp,200-201.) Friendly letter. Concerning natural history.
  - Letter to Lady [Kate Fanny Loder] Thompson [?], July 2; 7x4-1/2; Lankester, E. Ray (Edwin Ray), Sir, 1847-1929
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Album 1, pp.200-201.) Friendly letter.
  - Poem on the death of a friend., October 29, 1791; 5x7; Lavater, Johann Caspar, 1741-1801
    A(?).D.S.with initial. 1p. In German. (see Album 1, pp.266-267.)
  - Letter to _____ Ringgold, Sept. 9, 1800; Lavater, Johann Caspar, 1741-1801
  - Letter to [E.P.?] Oldfield, May 19, 1855; 6x4; Layard, Austen Henry, Sir, 1817-1894
    Venice, A.L.S. 3p. (see Album 2, p.31.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [E.P.?] Oldfield, Oct. 26, 1869; 7x4-1/2; Layard, Austen Henry, Sir, 1817-1894
    Naples, A.L.S. 4p. (see Album 2, p.101.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Wylie., 7x4-1/2; Leicester, Thomas William Coke, Earl of, 1822-1909
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. VI, p.52.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Sir William O.] Priestley, Nov. 12, 1890; 6x4; Lister, Joseph, Baron, 1827-1912
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Album 1, pp.14-15.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John Thomas] Quekett, 7x4-1/2; Liston, Robert, Sir, 1742-1836
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.12.) Business.
  - Letter to Sir Henry [Thompson], Aug. 17; 7x4-1/2; Lockyer, Norman, Sir, 1836-1920
    Grenada, A.L.S. 2p. (see Album 1, pp.178-179.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Miss Burrows, March 8, 1905; 9x7; Lodge, Oliver, Sir, 1851-1940
    A.L.S.with initials. 1p. (see Album 2, p.108.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John?] Milne, July 25, 1912; 9x7; Lodge, Oliver, Sir, 1851-1940
    Edgbaston, A.L.S. 2p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.25.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Sir Henry [Thompson?], April 29, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Album 1, p.194.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to C[harles] Voysey, London, Feb. 13, 1903; 5x4-1/2; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
    Biaritz, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. II, p.18.) Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to ----, Nov. 30, 1864; Luther, Karl T.R.
  - Autograph., Feb. 4, 1836; 5x4-1/2; Macauley, Thomas Babington Macauley, 1st baron, 1800-1859
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Album 2,p.43) Probably removed from a letter.
  - Autograph., 1-1/2x5; Maclean, John, Sir, 1811-1895
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. II, p.28.)
  - Letter to [Sir William?] Frazer, March 2, 1852; 10x8; Maclean, John, Sir, 1811-1895
    Fort Murray, A.L.S. 4p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol.II, p.26.) Friendly letter. Politics.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Owen., 7x4-1/2; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.20.) Forwards fossils.
  - Letter to ----, April 8, 1793; 9x7-1/2; Maskelyne, Nevil, 1732-1811
    Greenwich, A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.21.) concerning publications.
  - Letter to "My dear Charles" [Williams?], April 7, 1894; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Monier-Williams, Monier, Sir, 1819-1899
    Lewisham, A.L.S. 4p. (see Album 1, pp.6-7.) Concerning a publication.
  - Letter to Austin, Jan. 24, 1882; 7x4-1/2; Morley, John, 1838-1923
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Album 1, pp.83-84.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Quekett?], Aug., 1861; 7x4-1/2; Morris, John
    Manchester, A.L.S. 3p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p. 20.) Sympathy for Mr. Quekett. Refers to W. Buckland.
  - Letter to [Herbert Hall] Turner, May 27, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Newcomb, Simon, 1835-1909
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.19.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to E. Oldfield, London, Nov. 11, 1848; 10x7-1/2; Newton, C. T. (Charles Thomas), 1816-1894
    Rome, A.L.S. 4p.,add. (see Album 2, p.98.) Friendly letter. Concerning work at the British museum.
  - Letter to ----, Oldum, James
    A.L.S. 2 p.
  - Autograph., 4x4-1/2; Osborn, Sherard, 1822-1875
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Album 2, p.93.) Removed from a letter.
  - Letter to [William] Quekett, June 2, 1866; 7x4-1/2; Osborne, Sidney Godolphin, Lord, 1808-1889
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.7.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to "Dear Sir", Dec. 16, 1869; Osborne, Sidney Godolphin, Lord, 1808-1889
    Durweston, A.L.S. 8p. Discusses the type of congregation he prefers, the frequency sermons to be given and the present state of religion in England.
  - Letter to John [Thomas] Quekett, Nov. 22, 1848; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Paget, James, Sir, 1814-1899
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol, IV, p. 23.) Thanks for publication on microscopes.
  - Letter to Oldham, June 14, 1875; 7x4-1/2; Paget, James, Sir, 1814-1899
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Album 2, p.107.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Edwin] Waugh, Oct. 11, 1871; 7x4-1/2; Palgrave, Francis, Sir, 1788-1861
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Album 1, pp.111-112.) Friendly letter on literary subjects.
  - Letter to Crofton Croker, 10x8; Palgrave, Francis, Sir, 1788-1861
    Portsmouth, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Album 1, p.204.) Friendly letter. Not found April, 2011.
  - Letter to ----, 7x4-1/2; Pentland, Joseph Barclay, 1797-1873
    Thursday. A.L.S. 1p. (see Album 1, pp.232-233.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Douglas Murray, Jan. 12, 1896; 7x4; Petrie, W. Flinders (William Matthew Flinders), Sir, 1853-1942
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Album 1, pp.250-251.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Edward] Clodd, April 15, 1904; 7x4-1/2; Petrie, W. M. Flinders (William Matthew Flinders), Sir, 1853-1942
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.9.) Friendly letter. Accepts invitation.
  - Letter to Sir Henry [Thompson], Dec. 1, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Playfair, Lyon Playfair, Baron, 1818-1898
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Album 1, pp.183-184.) Concerning the biblical usage of petroleum and salt.
  - Letter to E[dward] Clodd, Nov. 10, 1881; 7x4-1/2; Proctor, Richard A. (Richard Anthony), 1837-1888
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.4.) Friendly letter. Asks him to write a paper on Egyptology. Refers to Clerk Maxwell.
  - Letter to Mrs. Blumberg, Nov. 14, 1882; 7x4-1/2; Quince, W
    A.L.S. 1p. (seeAlbums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p. 28.) Business.
  - Letter to Andrew, June 6, 1873; 7x4-1/2; Ramsay, Andrew Crombie, Sir, 1814-1891
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.18.) Concerning limestone.
  - Letter to ----, Oct. 15, 1911; 7x4-1/2; Ramsay, William, 1852-1916
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.4.) Will accept invitation. Refers to David Gill.
  - Letter to John [Thomas] Quekett, June 16, 1847; 5x4-1/2; Retzius, A. (Anders), 1796-1860
    Stockholm, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning peculiar hairs from a man.
  - Letter to [John Thomas] Quekett, London, Nov. 11, 1852; 10x8; Retzius, A. (Anders), 1796-1860
    Stockholm, A.L.S. 2p. Introduces Dr. Bonsdorff. Concerning microscope slides.
  - Letter to Sir Astley Cooper, bart., Feb. 10, 1837; 6x4-1/2; Roget, Peter Mark, 1779-1869
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. V, p.3.) Asks a favor.
  - Letter to William Clift, Feb. 20, 1827; 9x7; Sabine, Joseph, 1770-1837
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Albums ...; 1777-1917. Vol. IV, p.25.) Needs a surgeon for a ship.
  - Letter to Mr. Richards, March 15, [1847]; 10-1/2x8; Scott, Peter